y'all ready to hop into another ice bath
with me this time around we're rocking
with the ice barrel I've been freezing
my butt off with this bad boy for quite
a while so you know what time it is it's
time for me to break down my experience
for you guys
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back at
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time
around we've got the ice Barrel in this
video I'm gonna tell you everything that
you need to know about this cold plunge
from the price and the features some
things I like and don't like and of
course who should or maybe should not
buy one of these but before I get
started with all of that I gotta let you
know we've reviewed a ton of cold
plunges on barbin.com so if you want to
browse our best list just go and search
bar Bend best cold plunges you can find
out for yourself which one cracks that
number one spot
foreign
well for starters it's got a really
compact design which literally is in the
shape of a barrel it only weighs 55
pounds when it's empty so once you drain
it you can literally move this thing
around wherever you want speaking of
draining it that's a really simple
process thanks to the hose hookup
located right on the front of the barrel
the lid as well as the cover that comes
with your purchase are both designed to
keep your water temperature at that
exact temperature you want for around
one to three days but that could
definitely change depending on how hot
it is outside during the summer good
news is during the winter you might not
actually need ice which is really cool
okay so let's talk about a few issues
you might run into with the ice Barrel
let's talk about wastefulness first so
you're gonna have to use a lot of water
and a lot of ice with the ice Barrel so
definitely run into that problem of
being wasteful so just a little example
here when I first got mine you know I
put 40 pounds of ice in here and then
went to go fill it up with water oh my
ice was melted in about 10 minutes now
it's warm out you know it's middle of
summer right now so that definitely
impacted that a little bit but that's
definitely something worth mentioning so
I actually went and bought 40 more
pounds of ice dumped that in after the
water was all in there and that ice was
also melted so definitely something
worth mentioning right there I also
think it'd be really cool if there was a
seat built into the barrel itself that
way you know you have something to sit
on but it's also going to double as a
step for you to get out of the barrel
because it can definitely be a little
bit tricky when you go to get out and
obviously you're soaking wet the water
definitely gets cold don't get me wrong
but it might not stay as cold as some
other cold plunges that I've reviewed
for y'all you know especially when it's
hot outside because it might not be as
insulated you know as an acrylic or a
fiberglass tub may be lastly is going to
be the price you can purchase an ice
barrel for right around twelve hundred
dollars and you know I gotta say that's
pretty expensive considering it's a
plastic barrel and there's not a whole
lot of features here for you to work
with but you know at the same time if
you're somebody who's tight on space and
you want a designated plunging area this
is a good option for you and you know if
you're somebody who lives in a area that
gets really cold or stays relatively
cold then this is probably going to be
your best bet too since you won't have
to use that much ice
foreign
[Music]
okay so let's hop into the price now
once again you can purchase an ice
barrel for right around twelve hundred
dollars but once you tack on your
shipping it's basically 1300 bucks now
once again that's a pretty big chunk of
change for a plastic barrel with not
many features you could spend about
eight hundred dollars more or so and get
a cold plunge that regulates your
temperature and even filters your water
but you know if you're tight on space or
you know like I said you live somewhere
that gets really cold in the winter
months and kind of stays cold year round
this is a really really good option for
you to consider
foreign
[Music]
okay so since the ice Barrel does not
filter your water for you you definitely
want to snag that water maintenance kit
it's priced right around 130 bucks it's
going to include Epsom salt water
stabilizer cleaning soap a brush to
scrub the barrel inside and out as well
as a skimmer net and a thermometer now
you can purchase all of those separately
if you want to but you're probably going
to want it spending more money in the
long run you can also purchase a
replacement step stool stand lid and
cover if you ever need to foreign
[Music]
okay so when it comes to the build
there's really not a whole lot to
explain here it's a plastic barrel
everything here is in fact made of
plastic but it is insulated so once you
toss this lid on and you throw the cover
over it as well it's designed you know
keep that water temperature locked in
for at least a day maybe even up to
three days you know depending on the
temperature outside of course it's just
under four feet tall just under three
feet wide and the opening is a little
bit over two feet wide itself it can
hold up to 105 gallons of water it only
took me about 15 minutes for it to fill
up
[Music]
foreign
so let's talk accessories now everything
other than that water maintenance kit is
actually included with your purchase so
that's really nice now I'm talking about
the step stool the stand for the barrel
the lid and of course the cover it's all
going to come with that original
purchase but if you ever need to replace
any of these parts or you know maybe you
just want to get the skimmer net
whatever it may be you can head over to
their website you'll find all of the
accessories listed right there for you
so once again that water maintenance kit
is right around 130 bucks Epsom salt is
basically 16 water stabilizer is right
around 50. cleaning so it's about 15
bucks cleaning brushes about eleven
dollars the Net's around twenty dollars
at thermometer is around 14 now step
stool is about 46 bucks or so and the
replacement cover and the replacement
stand as well as the lid are all right
around a hundred dollars
foreign
guys let's go and do a quick walk around
now with the ice Barrel you know once
again this is all plastic right here it
is insulated though so once you have
this lid on here as well as that tarp
cover that goes over it you know that's
going to keep that water temperature
where you want it to be for at least a
day maybe even up to three days you know
depending on how hot or cold it is
outside draining the tub is super easy
all you have to do is hook up your hose
or not doesn't really matter and you can
twist this nozzle right here and that
water is going to free flow on out of
there now once again everything's made
of plastic that's including the stuff
it's including the stand right there and
you know what what kind of a video would
this be if I didn't hop in here so I'm
gonna do that but before
[Music]
why don't we go ahead and toss some more
ice in here
and let's get to it
it's cold all right
all right
all right so speaking of benefits who
should purchase the ice Barrel well this
is designed to be a space saver so if
you're tight on space and you do in fact
want yourself a designated cold plunge
this might be the best option out there
you know aside from using a bathtub or a
clean trash can hopefully it's clean
it's made of plastic so it's gonna be
super easy to clean it only weighs 55
pounds when it's empty so you can always
you know move it around whenever
necessary and finishing off with the
benefits you know there's a lot of
benefits with cold water therapy you
know from inflammation to Muscle
Recovery even overall brain health you
know it stimulates more blood flow to
your brain so if you want those benefits
I think this is a really good option for
you to consider
all right now what about the people who
might not want to purchase the ice
Barrel well
it's kind of expensive for a plastic
barrel right you know thirteen hundred
dollars is a you know good chunk of
change so you know you could always use
a bathtub or trash can even if you
wanted to but you know this is a nice
designated area it just might be a
little bit expensive for some people
talk about water regulation as well you
know water definitely stays cold in here
but it might not stay as cold as a cold
plunge that's made of acrylic or even
fiberglass and continuing with that you
know this isn't going to regulate
temperature for you so if you do want a
cold plunge it's going to take care of
all of that and you might want to check
out some other options that are online
well guys that's all I have for you
today on the ice Barrel you know this
thing's pretty sweet and I was a little
skeptical about the size of it at first
I've talked about my other cold plunge
videos that you know something like this
may lead to some heat pockets in your
legs but honestly I feel totally fine
right now I don't feel like I'm having
to deal with that whatsoever this is a
great space saving option you know it is
kind of expensive it's around thirteen
hundred dollars shipping so that might
be a bit of a turn off for some people
but in the winter months you know it's
really nice you might not have to deal
with any ice whatsoever thanks for
hanging out with me all I hope this
video was really helpful full and I was
able to answer any questions you may
have about the ice Barrel as always stay
posted for my next video but for now
head over to barbin.com you can read
more about this product right here just
search barvin ice Barrel review you'll
find everything that I talked about here
today I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]